# 这里刀的这个尖角
Here is the sharp cutting edge of the knife
# 这样子稍微用点力把这些膜撕破皮
Just like this, cut the membrane a little bit hard
# 然后用手这样子慢慢这样子刮
And then tear it away with your fingers slowly
# 好
Got it
# 才撕它得下来
In this way you can tear it away
# 嗨 大家好 我是漆二娃
Hi there, this is Qi Erwa
# 今天我要做一个懒人排骨
Today I will cook a Lazy Man's Pork Rib
# 现在我要把这层油给它撕掉
Now let me tear the oil tissue away
# 慢点 不要慌 等会撕不完
Take your time, no rush, or you can’t clean it thoroughly
# 好大一层油哦这个
How heavy the oil tissue is here!
# 是这样子撕的嘎四伯爷
Am I doing alright, uncle?
# 嗯 对对对看嘛 那块油
Absolutely, you are right, see the oil tissue on your hand
# 哦哟喂 这块油起码都有2两
OMG, this pork fat should have at least a weight of 100g
# 这样子就全部可以看到那瘦的了撒
Just like this, you can see all the lean meat
# 膜膜一蒙起你就看不到那瘦的
You can’t see the lean meat if the pork fat covers it
# 好安逸这 可以了嘎四伯爷
Awesome! We are done, right? Uncle
# 可以了可以了
Sure, sure
# 我把它洗哈
Let me clean it a little bit
# 看嘛 这点油拿来有什么用嘛
See, how to deal with such a small piece of pork fat?
# 把它切点来喂狗
Cut it and feed the dog
# 四伯爷这个从哪儿下刀哦
Uncle, where should I start cutting?
# 咋个下刀
How to start cutting?
# 你把那个肉留不留在上面吗
Will you leave the meat on the bone?
# 肉不留在上面就拼下来撒
If not, just scrape the meat off bone
# 要留在上面 要不你来砍嘛
The meat is on the bone, how about you chop it?
# 你才砍得来排骨 教哈我
You are good at chopping pork rib, could you show me how to do it?
# 好嘛好嘛 这个很简单的
Alright, alright, this is very easy
# 我教你一回看你下次你搞得会不
Let me show you, and see whether you can do it by yourself next time
# 菜板有点高嘎
The cutting board is a little bit high, ah?
# 那不是咋个安
Yeah, isn’t it?
# 哦 这样子
Oh, it’s like this
# 哦 晓得了
Oh, I got it
# 专业的是不一样嘎 经常宰到排骨得
Professional and impressive, as you chop pork rib a lot
# 哦 好简单哦这样子一哈都砍出来了
Oh, looks so easy and you get it done so quickly
# 好 就这样子
Alright, just like this is good enough
# 要得 懒人排骨的嘛就懒点
Sure, we are cooking Lazy Man's Pork Rib, just be lazy
# 整长节点
Let the pork rib piece be longer
# 要得
Sounds good
# 先切点柠檬
Firstly, cut some lemon
# 切片
Slice it
# 你要泡水喝不嘛四伯爷
Do you wanna make some lemon water? Uncle
# 安
Hmm?
# 泡水喝不
Wanna make lemon water?
# 喝过安
I had it before
# 你要不要尝一哈四伯爷
Do you wanna try it? Uncle
# 喝过
I had it
# 尝一坨嘛
Just taste one piece?
# 你尝
You do
# 那会儿我都整来怎么吃的呢 整来腌白糖
How did I eat lemon previously? I cured lemon with sugar
# 啊
Ah
# 哎呀 好酸哦
Oh my, how sour it is
# 挑战无表情吃柠檬
Challenge eating lemon without a grimace
# 不吃不吃 吃不得
No no, I can’t eat it
# 只有腌白糖吃 好吃
I can only eat it if cured with sugar, that’s yummy
# 现在切点姜
Now cut some ginger
# 整几根小葱
Get some green onion
# 可乐
Coke
# 好了
Alright
# 然后加点盐巴
And then add some salt
# 一会就跟开水一样 是嘛
It will be like boiling water later, right?
# 哇
Wow
# 该是嘎
Yeah, it is
# 跟它深水炸弹样嘎
Ah it’s like a depth bomb
# 再加点白糖
Add some sugar
# 糖多一点
A little bit more sugar
# 好可以了
Alright, that’s all
# 这个不要撒
Do you need this one?
# 不要
No
# 好可以了
Alright
# 首先在锅中加入适量的清水
Firstly, add moderate water in wok
# 再把排骨放下去
And then put the pork rib in it
# 我感觉这个排骨比我的排骨都大
I feel the pork rib is bigger than mine
# 然后加入料酒
And then add some cooking wine
# 开大火烧开
Boil the water on high heat
# 去浮沫
Remove the scum
# 再把排骨捞出来
Then take the pork rib out
# 下面把锅烧热
Next, heat the wok
# 加入准备好的可乐倒入锅中
Pour the prepared coke into the wok
# 再放入焯好水的排骨
Then put in the parboiled pork rib
# 再加两颗八角两片香叶
Then put two star anises and two pieces of bay leaves
# 烧开之后又去浮沫
After the water boils again, remove scum
# 因为伯爷牙齿不好需要烧很久
Because uncle can’t chew a lot we have to braise it longer
# 所以再加点可乐
So add more coke
# 开小火烧半个小时
Boil it for half an hour on low heat
# 再把柠檬 姜片 小葱夹出来
And then take the lemon, ginger and green onion out
# 再开大火收汁儿
Then turn to high heat to condense the sauce
# 这懒人排骨真的很简单就是烧的时间会比较长一点
The Lazy Man's Pork Rib is really easy, you just need to braise it for a longer time
# 如果你牙口好
If your teeth condition is good
# 烧个ten minutes也是可以的
You probably just need to braise it for 10 minutes
# 移过来点嘛
Move it closer
# 要得啊
Sure
# 吃嘛 夹来吃撒
Try it, take one
# 夹来吃四伯爷 伯娘
Have a try, uncle and auntie
# 好
Okay
# 这次咬得动 肯定很耙活
This time you can chew it easily, must be very soft
# 脱骨的了
The meat and bone are separated
# 肉是肉 骨头是骨头
Perfectly separated
# 真的这回可能是整耙了安
Looks like the pork rib is really soft this time
# 这个骨头不要了
Throw this bone away
# 哎呀
Ah!
# 我夹一坨大的
Let me take a large one
# 好耙
How soft it is
# 这伯爷咬得动
Uncle can chew it easily
# 一抿就烂了
Melts in the mouth
# 是啊
Yeah
# 因为炖了很久
Because we braised it a long time
# 嗯可以
Hmm, good
# 这中午的懒人排骨硬是拿给你整耙了
The Lazy's Man pork rib you made this noon is really soft
# 整来跟你师父的相差不远了
Close to your master’s
# 相差不远了
Close
# 嗯
Yeah
# 打得到好多分嘛
How would you grade it
# 打得到98分
I can give you 98
# 98分啊
Ah, 98
# 100分你是达不到的
It’s still not good enough for 100
# 我好开心哦
I am so happy
# 我要上天了
I am flattered
# 你不要太骄傲了撒你
Don’t be overly proud
# 给你们说了这个懒人排骨只有懒人才做的出来
Only lazy man can make this lazy pork ribs
# 还可以
Not bad
# 可以
Good
# 好吃
Yummy
# 这中午的这个懒人排骨拿给你整巴适了的
You did a good job on the lazy man's pork ribs this noon
# 多吃点四伯爷
Have more, uncle
# 好吃就多吃点
Have more if you like it
# 好嘛好嘛
Fine, fine
# 我都吃了几坨了
I had several ribs
# 这次你做的这个懒人排骨安
The lazy man's pork ribs you made this time...
# 我还是夸你一哈
I have to praise you
# 不愧是懒人做的懒人排骨
Lazy man made lazy man pork ribs indeed
# 这是在夸我呢还是在
Is this praise or
# 懒人做的排骨就
Lazy man made ribs
# 在夸你
It’s a praise
# 我怎么听出了其他的意思呢四伯爷
Why I heard something else, uncle?
# 不是的 懒人做的排骨今中午就不造假了
No, it is a real lazy man made authentic Lazy Man Pork Rib this noon
# 四伯爷还在强调懒人做的排骨
Uncle keeps emphasizing it is a lazy man made the ribs
# 懒人做的排骨就可以
The ribs are good if it is a lazy man who cooked it
# 嗯 开心 今天我觉得这个懒人排骨做的还可以
Emm, I’m happy, I feel the Lazy Man's Pork Rib is well made
# 颜色啊 各方面啊 味道那些啊
Colors, tastes, etc.
# 都还不错
Quite good
# 懒人排骨懒人做的他就要用心点晓得不嘛
Lazy man would pay more attention when making Lazy Man's Pork Rib
# 给我自己比一个
I'll give myself a big
# GOOD
GOOD
# 这个菜做得好不是因为我是懒人
I made this dish well not because I am lazy
# 是我真的做得好
I did a really good job
# 这个勤快人也一定会做得好的
So diligent man can do it well for sure
# 然后本期视频就到这里了哟
This video ends here
# 拜拜
Bye
# 放到等会吃饭的时候一起吃
Will have it later at lunch time